MISHAEL ABIOLA

Software Engineer

Professional Summary

Talented software development and Computer Science student experienced in producing and updating solutions to problems. Optimized structures and processes to accomplish customer targets and promote company loyalty. Expert in diverse object-oriented programming languages.

Motivated Graphic Artist skilled at creating letterheads, signage and other business specific materials. Talent for translating company vision into a suite of useful graphics and related designs.

Work History

Hoffenheim Technologies- Software Engineer and Developer 03/2019-Date

- o Project lead for various web development Project.
- o Developing solutions to various problems faced by companies
- o Backend Development with technologies like Laravel, smarty etc.

Solar Flares- Freelance Graphic Designer Lekki, Lagos 03/2019-11/2019

- Contributed design ideas in early planning stages with customers and project managers.
- o Put together graphics for social media, advertising and informational purposes.
- o Met with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments.

Bijamic Schools - Software Engineer Ajah, Lekki 10/2018 – 01/2019

- o Tested troubleshooting methods, devised innovative solutions, and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team use.
- Consulted with network engineering staff to evaluate hardware and software requirements for new system development.

Bijamic Schools – Information Technology Instructor Ajah, Lekki 08/2018 – 10/2018

- o Worked with Bijamic Schools to implement computer literacy program and technology use into day to day instruction.
- o Facilitated computer lab of about 20 students and designed appropriate and specialized lesson plans.
- Planned and implemented curriculum to teach up-to-date technology to over 50 students.
- o Coordinated ongoing technical training and personal development classes for staff members.

Accomplishments

- o Founding member of WusobTech LTD (wusobtech.com)
- o Participated in Google Hash Code 2020
- o Member of DSC Unilag (Developer Students club)
- Developed an innovative software package that automated the administrative sector and registration of students, we called it SDM (Students Database manager).
- Successfully completed a search engine application within budget and ahead of schedule for my school project along with my team.

Address

abiolamishael@gmail.com 08167406144 Lagos L.A 101245

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mishael-abiolanonymousray https://github.com/mishiray https://www.hackerrank.com/abiola mishael

Skills

- o Performance and scalability optimization
- o Software development
- o Data collection and analysis
- o Data analysis and Database development
- o .Net development
- Software testing
- Experience with Data Structures and Algorithms
- o Networking
- o Technical support
- o Advanced knowledge of C# and Java
- o Graphic design

Education

University of Lagos

2017 - 2021

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

I have learned how to be a proper software engineer and developer. Building well documented software that are ready for change and easy to understand.

I have also learned how to be a project manager, while I involved myself in various hackathons. My knowledge of data structures has increased greatly, so I develop using the best data structures for the project.

Certifications

Certificate of Participation in: Cyesec Tech cyber security and Esolutions Sololearn Fundamentals Certifications :Java, C#, Sql, C++